lakeland.co.uk 2019-07-19

# Privacy Policy

You can always trust Lakeland. Your personal information is just that – personal, so we always treat it with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, and rest assured, we never pass on, sell or swap your information with any other company for their own marketing purposes.

For over 50 years, we have been committed to looking after your data and we will always put you first.

## What information do we hold about you?

When you shop with us, register for an online account, ask us to keep in touch with you using your email address or choose to receive our catalogues, we collect information about you. We also collect information about you when you voluntarily complete Lakeland customer surveys, provide us with feedback or participate in our prize draws and competitions. If you browse our Lakeland website, we may collect information about your website visits using 'cookies' – click _here_ to view our full Cookies policy.

## How do we use your information?

Your information allows us to fulfil any orders you place with us, update you on the progress of your orders and assist with any future customer service queries.

We would also love to keep you up to date with our favourite products, exciting new ranges and unmissable offers we think will be of interest, by contacting you by post and using your email address to send you our email newsletters, communications via social media and any similar internet-based communications as they become available.

If you already receive our marketing communications, we’ll continue to send you these unless we think you are no longer interested in hearing from us or you ask us to stop. We hope you enjoy hearing from us just as much as we enjoy putting our updates together, and we promise never to bombard you with too many communications.

We may use your information, including details of your Lakeland purchases, how you choose to interact with us, your recent Lakeland website browser history and geographic information, to help us decide what we talk to you about and when. We may also use your information to create profiles of, for example, our most loyal customers, or to identify key interest groups, for example, those of you who appear to love to cook and bake. Ultimately, we want to make sure that our marketing communications are always relevant and interesting and this information will really help us achieve just that. Your information also helps us to tailor our advertising to those people who we think will really enjoy shopping with us too.

There are some communications that you’d always expect to receive from us, whatever your marketing preferences – for example, order confirmations by email if you have shopped with us online, or important order or customer service updates.

We employ the services of other companies to support our business for specific functions, for example: despatching orders (using nominated parcel carriers); processing payments (using nominated payment providers); despatching Lakeland marketing communications (using a small number of postal and digital communications service providers); and validating and analysing our customer data, including potentially updating addresses if customers have moved house (using a small number of nominated data specialists). If you order products from our website that are highlighted as will be despatched directly from our suppliers, we’ll securely transfer your details on to these suppliers so that they can fulfil your orders. For certain purchases, we may need to verify your identity with a trusted third party for fraud prevention and age verification purposes, in order to protect your interests and fulfil our legal obligations.

To deliver our products and services to you, we may need to transfer your data outside of the European Economic Area (EEA), for example if you are requesting delivery overseas or our service provider is based outside the EEA.

All third party service providers we work with are carefully vetted and highly trusted by us, and your data is protected by Lakeland’s stringent security and confidentiality measures as well as applicable data protection laws. We only provide our service providers with the data that they require in order to perform the services that we have employed them to do – they will never use your data for any other purposes.

Unless otherwise stated, our processing of your personal data, as summarised in this notice, is in pursuit of our legitimate business interests as a trusted retailer, committed to providing you with the very best shopping experience.

We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this notice. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold your data is 4 years. Everything you buy from Lakeland comes with a 3 year guarantee, so we like to hold on to the detail of your orders long enough so we can easily help with any queries you may have.

## Your rights regarding your personal data

If you receive our postal or email based marketing communications, you can choose to opt out at any time, and without any fuss or delay – simply give our Windermere-based Customer Services team a call on 015394 88100, chat with us online, email or write to us (click _here_ for more details). Alternatively, you can update the settings in your online account if you have set one up or click on the unsubscribe link that appears in every one of our email newsletters. Please note that you may continue to receive our communications for a short period after changing your preferences while our systems are fully updated.

You also have the right to: 

  * Ask that we correct or update any personal information that is incomplete, inaccurate or out of date.
  * Ask that we erase your personal data from our systems.
  * Ask that we stop processing your data or restrict processing where we haven’t compelling legitimate grounds which override your interests, rights and freedoms.
  * Request access to the personal information we hold about you.
  * Object to us profiling your data, where we haven’t compelling legitimate grounds which override your interests, rights and freedoms.
  * Request that any data provided by you in the context of actively consenting to some form of processing, be returned to you or transferred to another company in electronic form.
  * Lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) in the UK – please see below for more information.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please get in touch with us using the link below. Please note that we may ask for proof of identity before providing or updating any personal information we hold about you and if we have a legitimate reason as to why we are unable to fulfil any requests, we will always explain the reasons why.

## How to contact us

Our Data Protection Officer is always happy to help and answer any questions you have about our Privacy Promise. Simply write to them at Lakeland, Alexandra Buildings, Windermere, Cumbria LA23 1BQ or alternatively click _here_ for other ways to get in touch. If you have any reason for concern, please contact us in the first instance and we will do our utmost to resolve the matter to your complete satisfaction. Alternatively, you can report a concern to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) – click _[here](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/)_ for more details.

Last updated 16th May 2018
